# Suresh vakkalanka

Senior Software Engineer, Facebook

# Summary

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

11 years of IT Professional experience with well rounded skills as Engineering Manager, Lead Developer and Developer for Smartphone or Wireless software products in Samsung. Solid experience in managing multi-disciplinary teams of varying sizes and complex programs of work. Has the ability to build strong relationships with all stakeholders and to turn proposals into reality. Skilled in design, development and management in areas of Software Products, Mobile Platforms, Mobile Applications, Android Framework, Linux, Security, PKI, Samsung Knox, ARM TrustZone, Trusted Execution Environment (TEE), Cryptography, Mobile Payment, Smart Card, Secure Element, SELinux and SEAndroid.

#### SPECIALISED SKILLS

- 7+ years' experience in Android application, framework and system development.
- Lead complex software development projects through entire life cycle from requirement inception to execution.
- Deep understanding of Payment Domain and Samsung Pay architecture. Worked as an engineering manager for Samsung Pay Application for Spain (EU) and India.
- Good understanding of Samsung KNOX security platform and SE Linux.
- Strong knowledge in Linux kernel device drivers and board support packages for android.
- Fluent in Android SDK/NDK and device driver development.
- Proficient in end-to-end development of software products (SDLC) from requirement analysis to system study, designing, coding, testing, debugging, documentation and implementation.
- Experience implementing Agile Methodologies Scrum, and Lean with Kanban.
- Strong programming skills in C, C++ and JAVA in embedded environment.
- Project Management and People Management experience.
- Skilled in building, training and mentoring high performing teams.
- Performed various roles developer, architect, lead, manager as per organization and business needs.
- Ability to learn and adapt to new, complex development environments.
- Strong analytical and problem solving abilities.

# Experience

## Senior Software Engineer at Facebook

June 2017 - Present

## Android Systems Architect at Panasonic Automotive Systems America

November 2016 - June 2017 (8 months)

## Group Engineering Manager at Samsung Research India Bangalore

March 2016 - October 2016 (8 months)

Engineering Manager for Samsung Pay client application team. My role includes design of TEE and eSE based client architecture and guide the team in implementation of Samsung Pay android based application.

# Senior Technical Manager at Samsung India Software Operations

April 2012 - March 2016 (4 years)

## **Development Lead at Samsung India Software Operations**

April 2010 - April 2012 (2 years 1 month)

# **Lead Engineer at Samsung India Software Operations**

July 2005 - April 2010 (4 years 10 months)

## **Software Engineer**

July 2001 - April 2002 (10 months)

# Education

# **Indian Institute of Technology, Madras**

M.S. by Research, Image and Video Processing, 2002 - 2005

## **Osmania University**

MCA, Computer Science, 1998 - 2001

# Suresh vakkalanka

Senior Software Engineer, Facebook



Contact Suresh on LinkedIn